Some people seem to be confused as to why there would be outrage by people on this day, October 7th, condemning the actions of a resistance group.
And that is, in that sentence, why people are upset.
Because ultimately, to try and equate the reverence shown on this day to both parties is deeply problematic.
And also, to do so using information that has already been debunked is also deeply problematic.
And I know some people will say, well, no, we're not talking about the country.
We're talking about the people, the hostages, etc.
But the truth of the matter is that they are one and the same.
They're one and the same.
And that is what is being projected onto Palestinians.
When in actuality, that is the case for the country of Israel.
They have conscription service.
So everyone has done time as an IDF soldier.
Furthermore, they are the most polled people in the world, according to Norrin Frankenstein.
And they are constantly saying that they support the apartheid.
They support the occupation.
That they support the killing of the Palestinian people.
So it is not an individual scenario.
It's not a Netanyahu scenario.
This is a national culture.
This is a societal pathology.
Okay?
And so in understanding that, we have to understand that when we are trying to do an equation at the same time, in the same place, in the same space of something two years ago that we know is continuing now two years later on an exponentially higher level, we are completely dispossessing the truth of its power.
And we can't do that.
There's no way you can play both sides in this scenario.
And I know that some would like to say, well, no, we still want to honor the lives of them, etc., etc.
And the truth is that you cannot do that in the same space, time and breath as Palestinians without undermining the existence of Palestinians.
And that has always been the case.
And to do that furthermore, even in just the way that it's been contextualized, is you're speaking about the Israeli hostages and those who lost their lives first before addressing the Palestinians.
And if we want to just want to go on, if we want to just go around things, go about things chronologically, we know that Palestinians were losing their lives exponentially at consistent rates prior to October 7th.
So to come and acknowledge that today is deeply disturbing to those of us who know that in order for there to truly be a pro-Palestine movement, it has to be unwavering.
It has to be very clear in who it is centering.
And it has to be honestly unrelenting in that rigidity, in the morality and the ethics of that.
So I know there are people who are confused, who are like, I don't understand why it's a problem.
That, I hope, can give you some context as to why so many of us see it deeply problematic to now, at this point, also, when we have seen H Group several times capitulate and say,
we will release the hostages, please, we just ask for a ceasefire.
And to see that have been turned down over and over and over and over again, there should not be any mention of H Group, let alone ignoring the fact that their actions were contextualized in response to oppression, in response to occupation.
They are a resistance group.
And so if you're going to do the whole, we condemn, da, da, da, da, da, then just understand you are saying the same thing for slave revolts.
You're saying the same thing.
You're condemning prison uprisings.
You are condemning anyone who is fighting for their liberation.
So I want to make that clear because it seems to be unclear for so many of you from the river to the sea.